Contact

149 Bayview Terrace Akron, OH 44319 3306711076 (Home) rdevans87@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ ryanevanscreative (LinkedIn) www.ryanevanscreative.com (Personal) rdevans87.github.io/ RyanEvans_ProfessionalPortfolio/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Customer Service Technical Support Web Development

Languages

English

Certifications

Software Testing Bootcamp
Project Management Professional
(PMP)

Publications

Better Call 'Breaking Bad' Actor Aaron Paul

What Does 'Hardcore Henry' Mean for Moviegoers

The Discovery of Director Ryan Coogler

Rap Artist Kid Cudi Crosses Over Terrence Malick's Creative Magic

Ryan Evans

Technical Product Specialist/Full Stack Web Developer Akron

Summary

Independent web developer with leadership experience and strong technical background supporting a variety of cross-platform software applications. Certified project management professional and recent graduate of The Ohio State University's full stack coding bootcamp. In depth knowledge of Agile principles and software QA testing methods for each phase of the development lifecycle. Self-motivated, team-player with the ability to learn quickly and communicate effectively to build fast rapport with clients and team members of varying seniority, backgrounds and experience.

Experience

Freelance Web Developer January 2021 - Present (5 months) Ohio, United States

Full stack web developer open to independent projects, collaborative opportunities, contract-to-hire positions, and full-time employment. Knowledge of front-end languages and third-party frameworks for building mobile responsive web applications. Experience with DOM manipulation and JSON data integration with server-side APIs.

- Cloud application-platforms (Heroku), Command Line Interface (Git), MySQL database
 creation and management, object-oriented programming (OOP), object-relational mapping
 (ORM), model-view-controller(MVC)
- Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6
- Technologies/Libraries/Frameworks: Bootstrap, Materialize, React.js, Node.js, jQuery, HTTP

Requests, RESTful APIs, AJAX, CMS

• Development Methods: Pseudocode, Agile Principles, Scrum/Kanban, Mobile First, Wireframe

 Web Services: Blog, Small business, Restaurants, Real Estate, Special Events, Professional

Resumes, Creative Portfolios, E-Commerce

IMDb.com
Customer Service Specialist
July 2019 - Present (1 year 11 months)
Santa Monica, California

Acted quickly to diagnose and troubleshoot technical issues for IMDb's website and mobile apps under tight deadlines to meet 24-hour SLA.

- Collaborated with development team to file bug reports, track unresolved tickets, and manage customer relationships.
- Built fast and effective working relationships with team members of varying seniority, backgrounds and experience.
- Demonstrated ability to solve challenging technical issues and make datadriven decisions to improve customer satisfaction.
- Contributed to self-help knowledge base and implemented new support procedures that reduced incoming contacts and ticket resolution times.

Cast & Crew 3 years 4 months

Sr. Product Technical Support Analyst April 2018 - July 2019 (1 year 4 months)

Burbank, California

Managed product implementation efforts for all early adopters of Studio+ (SaaS) software as a file management and collaboration tool for each phase of film and television production.

- Acted as liaison between product manager and engineering team to communicate relevant software updates, product enhancements, and implementation requests to support team.
- Provided on-site/remote training demonstrations for end-users and established department best practices and policies for support team to follow and communicate to end-users.
- Assisted with QA testing, bug reporting, submitting end-user feedback, enhancement requests, and tracked software updates/releases using Agile project management with Scrum in Jira.
- Managed relationships through effective communication and collaboration between multiple internal and external stakeholders

Sales Support Associate, Final Draft Inc. April 2016 - April 2018 (2 years 1 month) Page 2 of 4

Burbank, California, United States

Responded to a high volume of incoming customer inquiries via phone, email, and live chat to drive sales and provide an excellent customer experience.

- Assisted with QA testing and software launch of two product releases: Final Draft 10 (2016) & Final Draft 11 (2018).
- Used Salesforce (CRM) to manage interactions with existing customers and identify new opportunities to increase sales.
- Performed in depth product demonstrations and sales presentations for industry professionals at screenwriting conferences and promotional events.
- Position required a strong attention to detail, exceptional service skills, and the ability to communicate effectively.

Unified Pictures
Production Executive
March 2015 - April 2016 (1 year 2 months)

Greater Los Angeles Area

Facilitated the relationship between financiers and executive producers on upcoming film projects.

- Communicated effectively under pressure during long periods of high call volumes to provide concise and accurate information to accredited investors.
- Gained valuable understanding of production workflow, budget costs, and private placement memorandums.
- Demonstrated flexibility and persistence to create consistent pipeline of accredited leads for finance department.

Macy's

3 years 3 months

Sales Supervisor March 2013 - March 2015 (2 years 1 month) Columbus, Ohio

Managed associates to provide the highest level of customer service through monitoring selling behaviors; taught detailed product knowledge, communicated policies and procedures.

- Demonstrated ability to lead a team to achieve daily sales goals and drive customer engagement with MAGIC selling best practices.
- Ability to analyze daily reports and identify opportunities to increase retail sales within assigned departments.
- Collaborated with merchandising team on upcoming promotional events and changes to department floor plans.

• Coached sales associates to connect with customers in order to build quick rapport and provide an outstanding shopping experience.

Sales Associate

January 2012 - March 2013 (1 year 3 months)

Columbus, Ohio

Duties included connecting with customers and assisting with their needs. Position required strong interpersonal skills, product knowledge, and the ability to multi-task. Demonstrated a proven track record of of exceeding daily sales goal and improving customer engagement.

University of Central Florida Production Assistant June 2009 - June 2011 (2 years 1 month)

Acted as Liaison for student affairs, responsible for maintaining a professional relationship between students and faculty at UCFtv. Duties included Floor Directing, Technical Directing, Running Teleprompter, Camera Operation, and Editing. Learned how to work effectively in a production team under tight shooting deadlines and television broadcast schedules.

Education

The Ohio State University

Professional Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Web

Development · (2021 - 2021)

University of Central Florida

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Communication and Media Studies · (2007 - 2011)